Based on the incredible true story of a businessman turned spy.
The Courier is a thriller, history, drama film directed by Dominic Cooke.
Cold War spy Greville Wynne and his Russian source try to
put an end to the Cuban Missile Crisis.
Greville Wynne, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Oleg Penkovsky, played by Merab Ninidze.
Emily Donovan, played by Rachel Brosnahan.
Sheila Wynne, played by Jessie Buckley.
Dickie Franks, played by Angus Wright.
Gribanov, played by Kirill Pirogov.
The Courier is a 2020 historical spy film directed by
Dominic Cooke and written by Tom O'Connor.
The film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Greville Wynne, and is based on the true story of a British businessman who was recruited by the Secret
Intelligence Service to be a message conduit with Russian spy source Oleg Penkovsky (played by Merab Ninidze) in the 1960s.
Rachel Brosnahan, Jessie Buckley, and Angus Wright also star.
The Courier had its world premiere under its original title Ironbark at the Sundance Film Festival on 24 January 2020, and
was theatrically released in the United States on 19 March 2021, and the United Kingdom on 13 August 2021.
The film received generally favourable reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia),
undercover, cold war, based on true story, mi6.
The tone is emotional and intense.